<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Robin Firth</title>
    <link>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Robin Firth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:42:04 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://forgottenmaster.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/posts/machinelearning/deeplearningfromscratch/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 01:17:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/posts/machinelearning/deeplearningfromscratch/introduction/</guid>
      <description>This series of posts will be my notes from the following book 
The main reason for this series of posts will be to allow me to create notes in my own words in order to understand the concepts being taught in this book.
One thing to note is that any code snippets I include in these posts will be in Rust, rather than Python. I will be using the Rust crate ndarray as my data structure, in lieu of numpy&amp;rsquo;s ndarray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/posts/machinelearning/deeplearningfromscratch/chapter1/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 01:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/posts/machinelearning/deeplearningfromscratch/chapter1/functions/</guid>
      <description>There isn&amp;rsquo;t too much to say for what a function actually is, since being a programmer, we use them every day. However for completeness I&amp;rsquo;ll include a post here.
For our purposes it will help to think of a function as a black box, that takes one or more inputs and returns an output. We can then chain these functions together by taking the output of function 1, and passing it to the next function and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/posts/machinelearning/deeplearningfromscratch/chapter1/derivatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:42:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/posts/machinelearning/deeplearningfromscratch/chapter1/derivatives/</guid>
      <description>Maths The derivative of a function is the rate at which the output changes with respect to a change in the input at a specific value for the input. This last part is important as the derivative of a function is essentially the gradient, or tangent of the graph of that function at a specific point which can of course change depending on where you are on the number line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Résumé</title>
      <link>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forgottenmaster.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>Ubisoft Reflections
Senior Gameplay Programmer
April 2020 - Present
As a senior gameplay programmer I have been responsible for architecting and implementing large systems in Assassin&amp;rsquo;s Creed VR. Where the product statement isn&amp;rsquo;t clear or is incomplete, I have worked with other disciplines to ensure the final design does what is required. During this time I have gained experience in Unity3D including DOTS and best practices for efficient programs. Additionally, I attempt to always share my knowledge as I develop it myself so as to allow others to also build their skills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
